<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Opinion | Chatswood]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/categories/opinion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-13T14:02:29+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maurice Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Try to Diagnose Yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/13/dont-try-to-diagnose-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-13T14:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/13/dont-try-to-diagnose-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve seen a lot of positive discussion in the developer community recently about depression and mental illness. People are standing up to say they have suffered from depression and that it is nothing to be ashamed of. This is good.</p>

<p>My only concern is that developers (being developers) have a tendency to try to fix things themselves. A developer spots a bug, spends a bit of time trying to root cause it, and then applies a fix. This is also good, in a development setting, but it’s not so good when dealing with what’s going on inside your own head.</p>

<p>If you’re feeling the <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Conditions/Depression/Pages/Symptoms.aspx">symptoms of depression</a>, then for your own sake talk to a friend or, better yet, go and see a professional. You might be a great developer but you are an amateur when it comes to understanding <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0596517785/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=0596517785&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-21">how your own brain works</a>. If you try to internalize it you are more likely to do yourself more harm than good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vesper]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/06/08/vesper/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T13:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/06/08/vesper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vesperapp.co/">Vesper is a new note-taking app</a> from Q Branch, a company comprised of the engineering talents of Brent Simmons, the design talents of Dave Wiskus, and the directorial talents of John Gruber.</p>

<p>So far opinion seems to be divided – many Apple bloggers are hailing it as the greatest thing since sliced bread, whereas many of the regular developers that I know or follow on some form of social media are of the opinion that it is over-priced and under-featured in an already saturated market segment.</p>

<p>Much of my own opinion on the matter can be summarised by <a href="http://www.leancrew.com/">Dr. Drang</a>’s <a href="http://www.leancrew.com/all-this/2013/06/form-and-function/">take: “Form and Function”</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Here’s a thought experiment: Imagine a new note-taking app written by an unknown developer. It’s has a nice, clean look and is easy to use, but it has no syncing, no TextExpander support, and no URL scheme. Assuming the app got any attention at all, how much effort would Apple bloggers put into defending that design choice? How often would the phrase “data silo” be used?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Personally, I’m a little jealous of the guys behind Q Branch. There, I’ve said it. As an iOS developer it smarts a little to see them get such acclaim for what is, by modern standards, a well designed but feature lacking app.</p>

<p>But what irks most is that this is symptomatic of much of what goes on in the Apple community these days. We have promoted certain individuals to the status of idols. We hang off their every word, we repeat their opinions in a parrot-like fashion, and we judge their work without the same level of criticism that we would apply to mere mortals.</p>

<p>We as a community need to stop this, otherwise we’re just the ‘fanbois’ we’ve always been derided for being.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netbot - The App.net Saviour?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/23/netbot-the-app-dot-net-saviour/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T14:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/23/netbot-the-app-dot-net-saviour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the <a href="http://www.muleradio.net/thetalkshow/20/">latest episode</a> of <a href="http://www.muleradio.net/thetalkshow/">The Talk Show</a>, host John Gruber commented with regard to App.net and the release of <a href="http://tapbots.com/software/netbot/">Netbot</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“It’s been a great little science experiment since Netbot came out about the importance of apps versus web clients”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Gruber, and his guest Brent Simmons, said a lot of sensible things in this discussion, but the implication here is that App.net was treading water prior to the release of Netbot because there were no native clients.</p>

<p>Many App.net users will be well aware that Netbot was not the first native iOS client to be unleashed. There were numerous native clients for iOS available prior to this (I personally used AppApp, <a href="http://tigerbears.com/felix/">Felix</a>, <a href="http://www.appnetrhino.com/">Rhino</a> and <a href="http://www.rivrapp.com/">Rivr</a>) so the native client requisite for success was already satisfied. The real reason why App.net usage took off after the release of Netbot was more likely due to a large volume of subscribers (existing and potential) who were too timid to truly embrace the platform until a big-name client was launched. </p>

<p>I’m glad that the release of Netbot for iOS gave a much needed boost to the App.net population and I hope we see a similar boost when Netbot for Mac is released. I’d also like to see some acknowledgement given to the original native clients who put in the hard yards in the early days. After all it was they who helped cultivate the existing population that made it viable for a bigger developer like Tapbots to invest in the platform.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweetbot for Mac Pricing]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T08:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed like an agonising wait for the Mac App Store review period to complete Tweetbot for Mac has now been released. The app went through a long (and strangely quite public<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>) alpha testing period and as a result there is very little to surprise the user in the finished product. Except that is, the price.</p>

<p>The sale price of $20 has ruffled a few feathers amongst the potential customers for Tweetbot. This is not surprising as there are few Twitter clients in the Mac App Store that sell for more that $5. Additionally Tweetbot for iPhone and Tweetbot for iPad are both priced at $2.99 making a $20 selling price a 666% increase in price for an app that does pretty much the same thing in a consumer’s eyes.</p>

<p>Personally, I feel that the $20 price tag for this piece of software is steep, but still justifiable. Tapbots have put a lot of effort into this application and they deserve some compensation. Additionally, they have to factor in the cost of <a href="/post/30606832645/maximising-bang-per-token">Twitter user tokens</a> meaning that they can’t rely on an ever-expanding user base in order to re-coup costs. I can understand some of the backlash to the price increase but this is probably more of a case of the previous clients being undervalued, as opposed to this client being overvalued.</p>

<p>I see this as a positive step, not just for Tapbots, but for App Store pricing in general. The long-discussed “race to the bottom” in app pricing can make it difficult for all but the most popular apps to survive. It is good to see a “headline” app take on realistic pricing and hopefully some of the smaller developers will gain the confidence to increase their prices in future. Higher prices will ultimately make for a more sustainable business model that allows small development companies to survive.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m holding onto my conspiracy theory that the Tweetbot for Mac went to alpha very early because Tapbots were tipped off somehow. The fact that the app was around for a while before user token limits were put in place gave Tapbots a chance to acrue more user tokens than they would have done otherwise.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Magazine is Not the Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T16:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Mac and iOS community got in all of a tizzy late last week following the announcement of <a href="http://marco.org/">Marco Arment</a>’s latest project - <em><a href="http://the-magazine.org/">The Magazine</a></em>, a foray into the world of publishing through the channel of the iOS Newsstand application. The basic premise is simple: a monthly subscription of $1.99 delivers you two issues per month direct to your iOS device. Each issue contains 4 editorials produced by a variety of writers.</p>

<p>The reaction to the launch has been favourable; not just for the actual product itself but the concept as well. <a href="http://www.macstories.net/news/marco-arments-the-magazine-at-the-intersection-of-technology-and-writing/">Federico Viticci (Macstories)</a> thinks that <em>”…The Magazine is a promising and notable initiative…”</em>. <a href="http://thenextweb.com/media/2012/10/11/instapaper-creator-marco-arment-launches-the-magazine-a-different-kind-of-periodical-for-apples-newsstand/">Matthew Panzarino (The Next Web)</a> described it as <em>”…a template for the future of lightweight Newsstand publications.”</em> Numerous comments across Twitter and App.net praised the initiative and suggested that it was an experiment in publishing.</p>

<p>Marco himself has described The Magazine as <em>“new and experimental”</em> and has set himself a limit for determining the success or failure for the “experiment”:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If it doesn’t turn a profit within two months — just four issues — I’ll shut it down. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>I think the praise is deserved - the application is a great reading environment, the writing is of a high quality, and the pricing is favourable. And while I agree that this <em>could</em> be a new business model for publishing I do not agree that Marco’s venture is how we should determine if the model can truly be successful.</p>

<h2 id="a-controlled-environment">A Controlled Environment</h2>

<p>To truly judge the success of an experiment or trial it must be carried out in a controlled manner and <em>The Magazine</em> is far from being launched in such a manner. Marco Arment is best known for being the creator of <a href="http://instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a>, and a co-founder of <a href="http://tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>. He has a very successful podcast called <a href="http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze">Build and Analyze</a> on the <a href="http://5by5.tv/">5by5</a> network. He writes a successful blog for which he can command <a href="http://www.marco.org/sponsorship">sponsorship revenues</a>. Marco is justifiably a bit of a celebrity in the Apple world and arguably in wider technology circles.</p>

<p>Like any astute businessman, Marco has been drumming up interest in his new venture for some time now, primarily through his podcast and to his many Twitter followers. It may not be a multi-million dollar advertising campaign, but Marco has enough of a loyal following to all but guarantee the success of <em>The Magazine</em>, in the short term at least.</p>

<p>That is not the only ace <em>The Magazine</em> has up it’s sleeve: the opening lineup of writers includes well-established players such as Jason Snell, Michael Lopp and Guy English. Marco has invited submissions from other writers with openings starting from issue four suggesting that the roster of big name writers may be set up for most of his four-issue trial period.</p>

<h2 id="the-real-experiment">The Real Experiment</h2>

<p><em>The Magazine</em> is great for the readers, great for the writers and ultimately great for Marco; it should be a huge success. It’s not so great for other budding publishers waiting to see if the business model works, especially if they don’t have the following that Marco has, or the access to top writing talent.</p>

<p>It reminds me of artists like Radiohead or Nine Inch Nails experimenting with self-publishing and distribution. They declare it a success when they sell a lot of copies and state it to be the future of music publishing. It’s not so easy for the up-and-coming artist who doesn’t have the established fanbase or production talent.</p>

<p>In my opinion the real experiment here is not the success or failure of <em>The Magazine</em>. It is instead in the success or failure of Marco Arment to diversify from his roots as a developer of software into a curator, an editor and a publisher. He has expressed a dissatisfaction with writing software in the past and his forays into podcasting, writing and public speaking have indicated a desire to get away from the coal face.</p>

<p>I hope that <em>The Magazine</em> succeeds because it places an emphasis on content rather than advertising. I hope it kick starts a new business model for publishing. But as someone who likes to see an individual succeed I’m more interested in seeing how Marco’s experiment with his career pans out.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
