<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Opinion | Chatswood]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/categories/opinion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-19T16:50:29+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maurice Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweetbot for Mac Pricing]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T08:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed like an agonising wait for the Mac App Store review period to complete Tweetbot for Mac has now been released. The app went through a long (and strangely quite public<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>) alpha testing period and as a result there is very little to surprise the user in the finished product. Except that is, the price.</p>

<p>The sale price of $20 has ruffled a few feathers amongst the potential customers for Tweetbot. This is not surprising as there are few Twitter clients in the Mac App Store that sell for more that $5. Additionally Tweetbot for iPhone and Tweetbot for iPad are both priced at $2.99 making a $20 selling price a 666% increase in price for an app that does pretty much the same thing in a consumer’s eyes.</p>

<p>Personally, I feel that the $20 price tag for this piece of software is steep, but still justifiable. Tapbots have put a lot of effort into this application and they deserve some compensation. Additionally, they have to factor in the cost of <a href="/post/30606832645/maximising-bang-per-token">Twitter user tokens</a> meaning that they can’t rely on an ever-expanding user base in order to re-coup costs. I can understand some of the backlash to the price increase but this is probably more of a case of the previous clients being undervalued, as opposed to this client being overvalued.</p>

<p>I see this as a positive step, not just for Tapbots, but for App Store pricing in general. The long-discussed “race to the bottom” in app pricing can make it difficult for all but the most popular apps to survive. It is good to see a “headline” app take on realistic pricing and hopefully some of the smaller developers will gain the confidence to increase their prices in future. Higher prices will ultimately make for a more sustainable business model that allows small development companies to survive.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m holding onto my conspiracy theory that the Tweetbot for Mac went to alpha very early because Tapbots were tipped off somehow. The fact that the app was around for a while before user token limits were put in place gave Tapbots a chance to acrue more user tokens than they would have done otherwise.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Magazine is Not the Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T16:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Mac and iOS community got in all of a tizzy late last week following the announcement of <a href="http://marco.org/">Marco Arment</a>’s latest project - <em><a href="http://the-magazine.org/">The Magazine</a></em>, a foray into the world of publishing through the channel of the iOS Newsstand application. The basic premise is simple: a monthly subscription of $1.99 delivers you two issues per month direct to your iOS device. Each issue contains 4 editorials produced by a variety of writers.</p>

<p>The reaction to the launch has been favourable; not just for the actual product itself but the concept as well. <a href="http://www.macstories.net/news/marco-arments-the-magazine-at-the-intersection-of-technology-and-writing/">Federico Viticci (Macstories)</a> thinks that <em>”…The Magazine is a promising and notable initiative…”</em>. <a href="http://thenextweb.com/media/2012/10/11/instapaper-creator-marco-arment-launches-the-magazine-a-different-kind-of-periodical-for-apples-newsstand/">Matthew Panzarino (The Next Web)</a> described it as <em>”…a template for the future of lightweight Newsstand publications.”</em> Numerous comments across Twitter and App.net praised the initiative and suggested that it was an experiment in publishing.</p>

<p>Marco himself has described The Magazine as <em>“new and experimental”</em> and has set himself a limit for determining the success or failure for the “experiment”:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If it doesn’t turn a profit within two months — just four issues — I’ll shut it down. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>I think the praise is deserved - the application is a great reading environment, the writing is of a high quality, and the pricing is favourable. And while I agree that this <em>could</em> be a new business model for publishing I do not agree that Marco’s venture is how we should determine if the model can truly be successful.</p>

<h2 id="a-controlled-environment">A Controlled Environment</h2>

<p>To truly judge the success of an experiment or trial it must be carried out in a controlled manner and <em>The Magazine</em> is far from being launched in such a manner. Marco Arment is best known for being the creator of <a href="http://instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a>, and a co-founder of <a href="http://tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>. He has a very successful podcast called <a href="http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze">Build and Analyze</a> on the <a href="http://5by5.tv/">5by5</a> network. He writes a successful blog for which he can command <a href="http://www.marco.org/sponsorship">sponsorship revenues</a>. Marco is justifiably a bit of a celebrity in the Apple world and arguably in wider technology circles.</p>

<p>Like any astute businessman, Marco has been drumming up interest in his new venture for some time now, primarily through his podcast and to his many Twitter followers. It may not be a multi-million dollar advertising campaign, but Marco has enough of a loyal following to all but guarantee the success of <em>The Magazine</em>, in the short term at least.</p>

<p>That is not the only ace <em>The Magazine</em> has up it’s sleeve: the opening lineup of writers includes well-established players such as Jason Snell, Michael Lopp and Guy English. Marco has invited submissions from other writers with openings starting from issue four suggesting that the roster of big name writers may be set up for most of his four-issue trial period.</p>

<h2 id="the-real-experiment">The Real Experiment</h2>

<p><em>The Magazine</em> is great for the readers, great for the writers and ultimately great for Marco; it should be a huge success. It’s not so great for other budding publishers waiting to see if the business model works, especially if they don’t have the following that Marco has, or the access to top writing talent.</p>

<p>It reminds me of artists like Radiohead or Nine Inch Nails experimenting with self-publishing and distribution. They declare it a success when they sell a lot of copies and state it to be the future of music publishing. It’s not so easy for the up-and-coming artist who doesn’t have the established fanbase or production talent.</p>

<p>In my opinion the real experiment here is not the success or failure of <em>The Magazine</em>. It is instead in the success or failure of Marco Arment to diversify from his roots as a developer of software into a curator, an editor and a publisher. He has expressed a dissatisfaction with writing software in the past and his forays into podcasting, writing and public speaking have indicated a desire to get away from the coal face.</p>

<p>I hope that <em>The Magazine</em> succeeds because it places an emphasis on content rather than advertising. I hope it kick starts a new business model for publishing. But as someone who likes to see an individual succeed I’m more interested in seeing how Marco’s experiment with his career pans out.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q. When is Apple news not actually news?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28971024283/q-when-is-apple-news-not-actually-news"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28971024283/q-when-is-apple-news-not-actually-news</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A. When you report old “news” as though it just “finally” happened.</p>

<p>Mike Schramm at <a href="http://www.tuaw.com">TUAW</a> posted the following last night:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple has finished smoothing out its Xcode releases with version 4.4.1, which finally brings Xcode out as a standalone app.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For some bizarre reason, Mike seems to have completely missed the Xcode 4.3 release that first introduced the concept of a standalone Xcode. (He also missed the 4.3.x point releases as well). Seems like sloppy “reporting” to me.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, as Apple has grown in stature, the number of websites covering Apple news grows at the same time. Venerable Apple news sites like TUAW are competing with upstart sites, and there seems to be a scrambling to report the tiniest little details as news.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naming and Shaming: Boss/Roland US]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/26368096042/naming-and-shaming-boss-roland-us"/>
    <updated>2012-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/26368096042/naming-and-shaming-boss-roland-us</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m fed up with receiving spam. I generally don’t get much of it because I tend not to publish my email address in too many places, and I use unique email addresses with every online store or service that I sign up to. This allows me to shut down an address when it starts receiving spam.</p>

<p>The other advantage of this system is that it allows me to see at a glance where the email address was obtained from. I can then take the appropriate action and inform the source that spam is being sent to an address that I trusted only with them. I <a href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/25222093783/dear-last-fm-i-hate-to-say-i-told-you-so">wrote about this at length</a> a few weeks ago when Last.fm and LinkedIn had their subscriber databases compromised. My biggest complaint with these companies and services is not the lack of security, it’s the lack of responsiveness.</p>

<p>I’ve been getting a bunch more spam this week to an email address that I used exclusively to sign in to the Boss US website (which was annoying in itself because I only wanted to download a product manual and had to hand over personal details to do so). I contacted Boss (and indirectly their parent company Roland) almost 2 months ago when the first spam arrived and received the following response:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Hello Maurice,</p>

  <p>We have forwarded your email to our webmaster for them to investigate this.</p>

  <p>Sincerely,
Roland US Product Support</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It seemed like a positive reaction, but unfortunately that was the last I heard. I’ve given them a chance but they’ve not taken the opportunity to visibly react. So now I’ve decided to name and shame Boss/Roland US.</p>

<p>You guys have had a security breach of some description. I’ve let you know, and you’ve still not gotten back to me. I have to assume that you’ve done nothing, or you’re doing it too slow. I’m telling the world because you’re not.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nobody Panic! Mac App Store Upgrades Solved]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/23496315143/nobody-panic-mac-app-store-upgrades-solved"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/23496315143/nobody-panic-mac-app-store-upgrades-solved</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today it looks like the <a href="http://blog.wilshipley.com/2012/03/mac-app-store-needs-paid-upgrades.html">question over how to handle major software updates</a> via the Mac App Store has been answered. </p>

<p>Mac (and iOS) developers <a href="http://panic.com/">Panic</a> have just announced the <a href="http://panic.com/coda/">details on the release of Coda 2</a>, their fantastic Web editor, the current version of which (1.7.5) currently sells in the Mac App Store for $99.99. Coda is a non-trivial app, one that has taken a lot of developer time and effort to produce. While many of it’s users would love to see Coda 2 replace 1.7.5 directly in a free upgrade, it was never likely to happen. On the flip side, it’s not appealing to pay the full new price again.</p>

<p>Thankfully Panic have managed to solve the problem by offering Coda 2 as a separate app. They have <a href="http://panic.com/coda/support.html">announced an aggressive 50% discount</a> for the first 24 hours that the app is on sale, making for an upgrade price of just $49.99. After 24 hours the price will go up to $75, which is still a respectable 25% off.</p>

<p>This is a great way to solve the problem. Loyal users can get 25-50% discount on the new version. And new users get a similar introductory discount. Not only that but people who are satisfied with Coda 1.7.5 still have a product that they can obtain support and bug fixes for, as well as re-downloading to new Macs. Overall, it seems like a win to me.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
