<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Chatswood]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-16T09:20:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maurice Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Defence of Mental Illness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2014/09/16/in-defence-of-mental-illness/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T09:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2014/09/16/in-defence-of-mental-illness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So… Apple paid U2 a lot of money to give away a copy of their latest album. The reasoning behind this has been discussed at length across the Internet and I could only speculate as to why either party did it. So I won’t.</p>

<p>The bigger controversy is the fact that Apple put a copy of the album into the purchase history  of every iTunes customer, which resulted in an automatic download of the album for many people. This also has been debated at length, and nobody really needs me to add another voice to the mix. So I won’t.</p>

<p>I was going to pass on this topic until I saw the following tweet written by Peter Cohen – a writer and managing editor at iMore, an Apple-centric news web site.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>I’m ambivalent about U2, but if you have actual rage that the album was added to your iTunes library, I think you’re mentally ill.</p>&mdash; Peter Cohen (@flargh) <a href="https://twitter.com/flargh/status/510206557632868352">September 11, 2014</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>I personally objected to Peter using the term “mentally ill” in this context. I thought about how I should send a scathing response, which is hard to do effectively in 140 characters or less, criticising Peter for equating general “rage” with mental illness, but I figured it was just a poorly worded, throwaway comment that wasn’t worth get annoyed about. So I didn’t.</p>

<p>Then I saw his article about the subject on iMore, <a href="http://www.imore.com/nsfw-apple-u2-and-looking-gift-horse-mouth">“NSFW: Apple, U2 and looking a gift horse in the mouth”</a>. While I don’t necessarily agree with his position on the whole subject, I once again was dismayed to see a reference to mental illness:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>But the inordinate amount of actual anger directed at Apple and U2 over this is so disproportional to the actual event, I’ve started to wonder about the mental state of some of those complaining. It’s really been off the charts.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’ve tried looking at it from Peter’s point of view, and I get that he has seen some people take this issue way too seriously. As with any broad cross-section of people, you can expect a wide spectrum of reactions, possibly ranging from ecstatic pleasure at receiving a free album by their favourite band of all time, to people who are – rightly or wrongly – angry, or raging, at what they see as a violation of their privacy).</p>

<p>Peter doesn’t get why people would be so angry. That’s fine. He wants to write about it. That’s fine also.</p>

<p>What’s not fine is conflating Internet rage (however extreme it may seem) with mental illness. It’s a cheap shot. It’s also quite disappointing given how much the tech industry has been pushing towards greater awareness of mental illness, and striving to reduce the stigma that has made it hard for people to seek help. Using a perception of mental instability to deride people you disagree with, is not the way to bring mental health issues to the fore.</p>

<p>As someone who suffers from mental health issues, I felt I should say something about this, and  do my part to not let people think it’s okay to equate rage with mental health problems. So I did.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deluxe Upgrades in iTunes]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/18/deluxe-upgrades-in-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T09:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/18/deluxe-upgrades-in-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, <a href="http://thepresets.com/">The Presets</a> – one of my favourite bands – <a href="https://twitter.com/ThePresets/status/368226816122556416">announced the imminent UK availability</a> of the “Deluxe/Expanded” edition of their <a href="http://pacifica.thepresets.com/">Pacifica album</a>.</p>

<p>As a fan, one of the most infuriating aspects of the music industry is the <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special_edition">Deluxe Version</a></em>. Some deluxe editions are re-releases many years later and contain “features” such as remastered tracks, expanded liner notes, and extra material. Other special editions are re-releases that come mere months after the original, usually offering a bunch of extra tracks and little else. In the case of Pacifica, the deluxe edition comes twelve months after the initial release with a bunch of remixes.</p>

<p>I’m a compulsive music buyer, and I love to buy music by my favourite bands on the day they get released. An unfortunate side-effect of being a dedicated fan is that loyalty is not rewarded by the release of a deluxe edition. The dedicated fan gets what amounts to an inferior product, and an “opportunity” to buy much of the same material again. When it came to physical discs, buying the original CD again just to get a few extra tracks was simply not an option. So in the past, I just grumbled to myself and got on with it.</p>

<h2 id="a-digital-upgrade">A Digital Upgrade</h2>

<p>These days I buy music from iTunes, where tracks can be bought individually and albums can theoretically be upgraded. Re-releasing an album as a deluxe edition could be a case of adding a bunch of tracks to the existing album, and allowing previous purchasers to <em>add</em> the new material at an additional (but discounted!) cost. I’m not saying we should just get them for free, I just feel that we should get an opportunity to get the same tracklisting as a new purchaser, without having to pay double (or potentially more than double).</p>

<p>This is completely feasible in this day and age. In fact, when I view the new <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/album/pacifica-deluxe-version/id687410130">deluxe edition of Pacifica on iTunes</a> it actually shows that I have purchased the original album tracks.</p>

<p><img src="http://content.chatswood.org.uk/photo/2013/08/presets-deluxe-edition-on-itunes.png" alt="Pacifica Deluxe Edition on iTunes showing previously Purchased tracks" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately I can’t simply buy the additional material – the entire Deluxe Edition is marked as Album Only. Even if they could be purchased separately it would actually cost more to buy the additional 12 tracks at 79p each than to buy the Deluxe Edition as a whole.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-want">What I Want</h2>

<p>I’d like to make it clear that I don’t blame The Presets, and am only mentioning them specifically as they were an example that triggered this post. It happens with deluxe editions from many artists, and in my opinion this falls squarely at the feet of the record companies and Apple/iTunes.</p>

<p>The record companies like to put out deluxe editions to bolster sales and extract more money from previous purchasers. They did it with physical discs and they are continuing the practice into the digital download age as well. </p>

<p>Apple/iTunes should be making more of an effort to allow “upgrading” to a deluxe edition. iTunes already has the facility to allow a customer to buy a few individual tracks from an album, then “upgrade” to the full album for the difference in price. A deluxe upgrade price could be set and purchasers of the original album could be offered a nominal upgrade price rather than being fleeced for the entire album again.</p>

<p>If iTunes provided this facility, and/or record companies treated the fans with a little less contempt, then it’s likely to be a win for everyone. Superfans don’t feel like they are being fleeced, bands can release deluxe editions without feeling like they are taking advantage of their fans, and the music industry could probably make more money from many “upgrades” than from the lower number of fans who would re-buy the entire album.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Try to Diagnose Yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/13/dont-try-to-diagnose-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-13T14:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/13/dont-try-to-diagnose-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve seen a lot of positive discussion in the developer community recently about depression and mental illness. People are standing up to say they have suffered from depression and that it is nothing to be ashamed of. This is good.</p>

<p>My only concern is that developers (being developers) have a tendency to try to fix things themselves. A developer spots a bug, spends a bit of time trying to root cause it, and then applies a fix. This is also good, in a development setting, but it’s not so good when dealing with what’s going on inside your own head.</p>

<p>If you’re feeling the <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Conditions/Depression/Pages/Symptoms.aspx">symptoms of depression</a>, then for your own sake talk to a friend or, better yet, go and see a professional. You might be a great developer but you are an amateur when it comes to understanding <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0596517785/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=0596517785&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-21">how your own brain works</a>. If you try to internalize it you are more likely to do yourself more harm than good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mastering Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/02/mastering-xcode/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-02T23:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/08/02/mastering-xcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After many months in the making, I’m pleased to be able to announce that the 2nd edition of Mastering Xcode is now available to purchase, and even more pleased to announce my involvement in the book as co-author.</p>

<p><a href="http://joshua.nozzi.name/">Joshua Nozzi’s</a> 1st edition was an invaluable reference for me as I started the process of transitioning to developing iOS and Mac software. The prospect of a 2nd edition was made even more exciting when Josh asked me to get involved in the production process. I initially came on as technical editor, but due to Josh’s other commitments I was fortunate to be asked to come on-board as a writer.</p>

<p>I’d done some technical writing in the past for UK magazines PC Plus and Linux Format, but this was the first time I’d ever been involved in the production of a book. The experience was challenging, and often time consuming, but ultimately very rewarding.</p>

<h2 id="about-the-book">About the Book</h2>

<p>Mastering Xcode is a guide to using Xcode from a first introduction to what I like to think of an “advanced intermediate” level. The first section is a gentle introduction to the environment. The second section is a ramp up to using the editor, workspaces, interface builder, the debugger and core data modeler to produce a simple “suite” of applications. The third section dives into more advanced topics such as the build system, debugging and profiling, as well as more detailed examinations of Xcode’s command line tools and SCM integrations.</p>

<p>While we couldn’t cover every facet of Xcode we have endeavoured to touch on as much as possible. We’re also acutely aware of the fact that this book is focussed on Xcode 4.6, which will likely be superseded by Xcode 5 later this year. We feel that much of the information in the book will still be relevant (even if it looks a little different). We’re also planning some “delta” material that will document what is new and what is changing – keep an eye on the <a href="http://xcodebook.com/">book website</a> for more information on that.</p>

<h2 id="saying-thank-you">Saying Thank You</h2>

<p>From a personal perspective, I’d like to thank Josh for giving me the opportunity to work on this book with him. He, and publisher Cliff Colby at Peachpit, let a cheeky individual finaigle his way into the process, and decided to take a chance on him. For that I’m exceptionally grateful.</p>

<p>I couldn’t have devoted the time needed to complete this project without the support of my wife and family. Whether it was giving up our evenings together, or taking the kids away to give me “writing weekends”, the efforts that they went to in order to help the process along was invaluable.</p>

<p>In the production process itself, our production editor Robyn Thomas was amazing. She guided us every step of the way, and gave re-assuring feedback when confidence was waning. From a technical perspective we have <a href="http://alpha.app.net/marramgrass">Mark Goody</a> to thank. His eye for detail kept us on track and made sure we weren’t misleading the reader too much.</p>

<h2 id="getting-the-book">Getting the Book</h2>

<p>If you are interested in getting a copy then please consider using one of the affiliate links below:</p>

<p>Peachpit Press: <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/link?id=34OBL5N2vk4&amp;offerid=163295.1865024&amp;type=2&amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.peachpit.com%2Fstore%2Fproduct.aspx%3Fisbn%3D0321861620">Print edition</a> - <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/link?id=34OBL5N2vk4&amp;offerid=163295.1865246&amp;type=2&amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.peachpit.com%2Fstore%2Fproduct.aspx%3Fisbn%3D0133091228">Ebook edition</a></p>

<p>Amazon UK: <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0321861620/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=0321861620&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-21">Print edition</a> - <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00DVLGLEY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=19450&amp;creativeASIN=B00DVLGLEY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-21">Kindle edition</a></p>

<p>Amazon US: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321861620/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321861620&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-20">Print edition</a> - <a href="ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DVLGLEY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DVLGLEY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=chatswood-20">Kindle edition</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vesper]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/06/08/vesper/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T13:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2013/06/08/vesper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vesperapp.co/">Vesper is a new note-taking app</a> from Q Branch, a company comprised of the engineering talents of Brent Simmons, the design talents of Dave Wiskus, and the directorial talents of John Gruber.</p>

<p>So far opinion seems to be divided – many Apple bloggers are hailing it as the greatest thing since sliced bread, whereas many of the regular developers that I know or follow on some form of social media are of the opinion that it is over-priced and under-featured in an already saturated market segment.</p>

<p>Much of my own opinion on the matter can be summarised by <a href="http://www.leancrew.com/">Dr. Drang</a>’s <a href="http://www.leancrew.com/all-this/2013/06/form-and-function/">take: “Form and Function”</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Here’s a thought experiment: Imagine a new note-taking app written by an unknown developer. It’s has a nice, clean look and is easy to use, but it has no syncing, no TextExpander support, and no URL scheme. Assuming the app got any attention at all, how much effort would Apple bloggers put into defending that design choice? How often would the phrase “data silo” be used?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Personally, I’m a little jealous of the guys behind Q Branch. There, I’ve said it. As an iOS developer it smarts a little to see them get such acclaim for what is, by modern standards, a well designed but feature lacking app.</p>

<p>But what irks most is that this is symptomatic of much of what goes on in the Apple community these days. We have promoted certain individuals to the status of idols. We hang off their every word, we repeat their opinions in a parrot-like fashion, and we judge their work without the same level of criticism that we would apply to mere mortals.</p>

<p>We as a community need to stop this, otherwise we’re just the ‘fanbois’ we’ve always been derided for being.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iTunes (not for) U]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/12/24/itunes-not-for-u/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T11:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/12/24/itunes-not-for-u</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t figure out how to play <strong>local</strong> <em>iTunes U</em> content on my iPhone - it just doesn’t appear on my device.</p>

<p>I like to download tutorial and training material (from sites like <a href="http://railscasts.com/">Railscasts</a>, <a href="http://ideveloper.tv/">iDeveloper TV</a>, <a href="https://peepcode.com/">PeepCode</a> and <a href="https://mijingo.com/">Mijingo</a>) and I’m one of these people who likes to hold onto the material <em>just in case</em> I ever need to watch it again. For convenience I dump it into iTunes on my Mac Mini that serves up content to a number of Apple TV and iOS devices. Because I’ve got a thing for organization, I like to mark the videos as being <em>iTunes U</em> material so that I can get to it easily through the Apple TV menus.</p>

<p>Sometimes I’m not using the Apple TV and I want to watch a quick tutorial on my iPhone. This happened the other night when I decided to watch a <a href="http://railscasts.com/">Railscast</a>. So I opened up the <em>iTunes U</em> app on the iPhone. It gives me the option to get official material from the catalog, but doesn’t let me browse my local Home Sharing machine.</p>

<p>So I tried the <em>Videos</em> app - it does let you choose Shared libraries, but only displays the categories <em>Movies</em>, <em>TV Shows</em>, and <em>Music Videos</em>. No sign of <em>iTunes U</em> content.</p>

<p>In desperation I tried the <em>Music</em> (formerly iPod) app but it didn’t include the option for <em>iTunes U</em> content (and hasn’t since <em>iTunes U</em> was split off into its own app a while back).</p>

<p>This seemed weird - I couldn’t find a way to play iTunes U material stored on my local server. Strangely, when I picked up my iPad mini the Videos app there has a section for iTunes U material (and I was able to watch the <a href="http://railscasts.com/">Railscast</a> absolutely fine - “panic” over).</p>

<p>Seems like quite an oversight that there is no way to carry out this (admittedly edge) use-case on an iPhone. Time for a Radar…</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mail.app and Power Nap]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/12/02/mail-dot-app-and-power-nap/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T12:05:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/12/02/mail-dot-app-and-power-nap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mountain Lion has been with us for several months now and has been a pretty solid release with some nice new features. One of those <a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/whats-new/">features is Power Nap</a> - the ability for a certain Macs to sleep with one eye open. It allows for the updating of data (fetching mail, contact updates, etc) and the performing of housekeeping tasks (carrying out backups and downloading software updates) while your Mac give sthe impression of being asleep.</p>

<p>I have a nice shiny 2012 <a href="http://www.apple.com/macbookair/">MacBook Air</a> so I’ve been getting these Power Nap features for free since upgrading to Mountain Lion. Generally I don’t notice it much - I have notifications from Messages already onscreen when I open my machine in the morning, software updates are quick to apply because they have already been downloaded and, most usefully, I can see new entries in my mailbox that arrived overnight.</p>

<p>So far, so good. There’s just one gripe with the way the mail messages arrive. I have an IMAP account that gets updated with new messages. But if I have viewed those messages on my iPhone/iPad or on another Mac, they don’t get marked as read via Power Nap. This seems like a minor inconvenience as the next refresh of the IMAP account should update their read/unread status.</p>

<p>Nope. Checking for new mail in all accounts doesn’t change the status. In fact, basic testing has shown that once woken from Power Nap I can’t even pick up new items in the IMAP mailbox. A restart of Mail.app is required before any updates to that mailbox are detected. It just seems to be the one IMAP account though - I have 3 other mail accounts (2 GMail and 1 iCloud) that update fine.</p>

<p>I guess it’s time to file a bug.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netbot - The App.net Saviour?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/23/netbot-the-app-dot-net-saviour/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T14:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/23/netbot-the-app-dot-net-saviour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the <a href="http://www.muleradio.net/thetalkshow/20/">latest episode</a> of <a href="http://www.muleradio.net/thetalkshow/">The Talk Show</a>, host John Gruber commented with regard to App.net and the release of <a href="http://tapbots.com/software/netbot/">Netbot</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“It’s been a great little science experiment since Netbot came out about the importance of apps versus web clients”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Gruber, and his guest Brent Simmons, said a lot of sensible things in this discussion, but the implication here is that App.net was treading water prior to the release of Netbot because there were no native clients.</p>

<p>Many App.net users will be well aware that Netbot was not the first native iOS client to be unleashed. There were numerous native clients for iOS available prior to this (I personally used AppApp, <a href="http://tigerbears.com/felix/">Felix</a>, <a href="http://www.appnetrhino.com/">Rhino</a> and <a href="http://www.rivrapp.com/">Rivr</a>) so the native client requisite for success was already satisfied. The real reason why App.net usage took off after the release of Netbot was more likely due to a large volume of subscribers (existing and potential) who were too timid to truly embrace the platform until a big-name client was launched. </p>

<p>I’m glad that the release of Netbot for iOS gave a much needed boost to the App.net population and I hope we see a similar boost when Netbot for Mac is released. I’d also like to see some acknowledgement given to the original native clients who put in the hard yards in the early days. After all it was they who helped cultivate the existing population that made it viable for a bigger developer like Tapbots to invest in the platform.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working With Drafts in Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/21/working-with-drafts-in-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T18:03:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/21/working-with-drafts-in-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having recently moved to an Octopress blog I’ve been revelling in the geekery of managing my posts from the command line. I was previously using <a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit">MarsEdit</a> to manage my posting to Tumblr, but that’s not as viable an option any more. This is a shame because I like MarsEdit and I especially liked the ability to work with local draft posts, something that Octopress (and the underlying Jekyll framework) does not natively provide.</p>

<p>Judging by a quick Google search on the subject I’m not the only person who has been thinking about this. Even the mighty <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/">Brett Terpstra</a> recently <a href="https://posts.app.net/1076717">posted to App.net</a> saying that he’d implemented a <code>rake draft</code> option (among other goodies) that stores drafts to a <code>_drafts</code> folder. This seems to be an avenue that <a href="http://blog.yangmeyer.de/blog/2012/05/28/octopress-drafts">other people are going down</a> but I’m not sure about the need for this separation.</p>

<p>Jekyll already offers the facility to mark a post as published using an attribute in the YAML front matter. When <code>published: false</code> is specified the post will not be output to the <code>public</code> folder as part of the <code>rake generate</code> task. It therefore will not be included in a <code>deploy</code> operation, which is exactly as we would expect, but makes it harder to see the draft posts in the context of the blog.</p>

<p>Interestingly though when using the <code>rake watch</code> or <code>rake preview</code> tasks, posts with an attribute of <code>published: false</code> <em>are</em> included in the generation of posts. When you point your browser to <code>localhost:4000</code> (or via a <a href="http://pow.cx">Pow</a> configuration) then you’ll see your unpublished posts included as though they were published. For me, this negates the need to create a dedicated drafts folder.</p>

<p>There are still failings with this approach: drafts are mixed in with published posts requiring file inspection to manually separate them, and the date given to the post (crucially updating both the YAML front matter and the filename) will be the creation date rather than the publishing date.</p>

<p>To facilitate this workflow I updated the Rakefile to include a few more default YAML attributes for a new post (defaulting <code>published</code> to <code>false</code>). Most importantly it includes a Rake task called <code>publish_draft</code> that lists all the posts with a <code>published</code> status of <code>false</code> and allows the user to select a post. The post can then be published using the current date (updating the YAML and the filename) or it can simply be published with the original date. You can find this Rake task in the Gist below - please take care as it has not been made 100% foolproof that this stage.</p>

<div><script src="https://gist.github.com/3927558.js"></script>
<noscript><pre><code>require &quot;preamble&quot;

desc &quot;Publish draft&quot;
task :publish_draft do
  posts_path = &quot;#{source_dir}/#{posts_dir}&quot;
  puts &quot;Listing drafts in #{posts_path}...&quot;

  drafts = Array.new()
  Dir.glob(&quot;#{posts_path}/*.*&quot;).each_with_index do |post, idx|
    yaml = Preamble.load(post)
    published = yaml[0][&quot;published&quot;]
    if published == false
      post_shortname = post.gsub(/#{posts_path}\//, &#39;&#39;)
      drafts.push(post_shortname)
    end
  end

  if drafts.length == 0
    puts &quot;### There are no drafts at present.&quot;
    exit 0
  end

  post_options = Array.new(drafts.length)
  drafts.each_with_index do |draft_post, idx|
    post_options[idx] = &quot;#{idx}&quot;
    puts &quot;  [#{idx}]  #{draft_post}&quot;
  end

  publish_index = ask(&quot;Which post would you like to publish&quot;, post_options)

  post_shortname = drafts[publish_index.to_i]
  post_path = &quot;#{posts_path}/#{post_shortname}&quot;
  yaml = Preamble.load(post_path);
  puts &quot;  Post details:&quot;
  puts &quot;    Title:\t#{yaml[0][&quot;title&quot;]}&quot;
  puts &quot;    Date:\t#{yaml[0][&quot;date&quot;]}&quot;
  puts
  publish_option = ask(&quot;Publish with current date (p), existing date (e) or cancel (c)&quot;, [&#39;p&#39;, &#39;e&#39;, &#39;c&#39;])

  if publish_option == &#39;c&#39;
    exit 0
  elsif publish_option == &#39;p&#39;
    puts &quot;Publishing with current date&quot;
    yaml[0][&quot;published&quot;] = true
    yaml[0][&quot;date&quot;] = Time.now.strftime(&#39;%Y-%m-%d %H:%M&#39;)

    matchData = post_shortname.match(/^\d{4}-\d{1,2}-\d{1,2}-(.*)$/)
    title_from_filename = matchData[1];

    new_post_path = &quot;#{posts_path}/#{Time.now.strftime(&#39;%Y-%m-%d&#39;)}-#{title_from_filename}&quot;
    File::delete(post_path)

    open(new_post_path, &#39;w&#39;) do |write_post|
      write_post.puts yaml[0].to_yaml
      write_post.puts &quot;---&quot;
      write_post.puts yaml[1]
    end

    puts &quot;The post has been published as #{new_post_path}&quot;

  elsif publish_option == &#39;e&#39;
    puts &quot;Publishing with existing date&quot;
    yaml[0][&quot;published&quot;] = true
    open(post_path, &#39;w&#39;) do |write_post|
      write_post.puts yaml[0].to_yaml
      write_post.puts &quot;---&quot;
      write_post.puts yaml[1]
    end
  end
end</code></pre></noscript></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweetbot for Mac Pricing]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T08:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/19/tweetbot-for-mac-pricing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed like an agonising wait for the Mac App Store review period to complete Tweetbot for Mac has now been released. The app went through a long (and strangely quite public<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>) alpha testing period and as a result there is very little to surprise the user in the finished product. Except that is, the price.</p>

<p>The sale price of $20 has ruffled a few feathers amongst the potential customers for Tweetbot. This is not surprising as there are few Twitter clients in the Mac App Store that sell for more that $5. Additionally Tweetbot for iPhone and Tweetbot for iPad are both priced at $2.99 making a $20 selling price a 666% increase in price for an app that does pretty much the same thing in a consumer’s eyes.</p>

<p>Personally, I feel that the $20 price tag for this piece of software is steep, but still justifiable. Tapbots have put a lot of effort into this application and they deserve some compensation. Additionally, they have to factor in the cost of <a href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30606832645/maximising-bang-per-token">Twitter user tokens</a> meaning that they can’t rely on an ever-expanding user base in order to re-coup costs. I can understand some of the backlash to the price increase but this is probably more of a case of the previous clients being undervalued, as opposed to this client being overvalued.</p>

<p>I see this as a positive step, not just for Tapbots, but for App Store pricing in general. The long-discussed “race to the bottom” in app pricing can make it difficult for all but the most popular apps to survive. It is good to see a “headline” app take on realistic pricing and hopefully some of the smaller developers will gain the confidence to increase their prices in future. Higher prices will ultimately make for a more sustainable business model that allows small development companies to survive.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m holding onto my conspiracy theory that the Tweetbot for Mac went to alpha very early because Tapbots were tipped off somehow. The fact that the app was around for a while before user token limits were put in place gave Tapbots a chance to acrue more user tokens than they would have done otherwise.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Magazine is Not the Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T16:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/blog/2012/10/15/the-magazine-is-not-the-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Mac and iOS community got in all of a tizzy late last week following the announcement of <a href="http://marco.org/">Marco Arment</a>’s latest project - <em><a href="http://the-magazine.org/">The Magazine</a></em>, a foray into the world of publishing through the channel of the iOS Newsstand application. The basic premise is simple: a monthly subscription of $1.99 delivers you two issues per month direct to your iOS device. Each issue contains 4 editorials produced by a variety of writers.</p>

<p>The reaction to the launch has been favourable; not just for the actual product itself but the concept as well. <a href="http://www.macstories.net/news/marco-arments-the-magazine-at-the-intersection-of-technology-and-writing/">Federico Viticci (Macstories)</a> thinks that <em>”…The Magazine is a promising and notable initiative…”</em>. <a href="http://thenextweb.com/media/2012/10/11/instapaper-creator-marco-arment-launches-the-magazine-a-different-kind-of-periodical-for-apples-newsstand/">Matthew Panzarino (The Next Web)</a> described it as <em>”…a template for the future of lightweight Newsstand publications.”</em> Numerous comments across Twitter and App.net praised the initiative and suggested that it was an experiment in publishing.</p>

<p>Marco himself has described The Magazine as <em>“new and experimental”</em> and has set himself a limit for determining the success or failure for the “experiment”:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If it doesn’t turn a profit within two months — just four issues — I’ll shut it down. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>I think the praise is deserved - the application is a great reading environment, the writing is of a high quality, and the pricing is favourable. And while I agree that this <em>could</em> be a new business model for publishing I do not agree that Marco’s venture is how we should determine if the model can truly be successful.</p>

<h2 id="a-controlled-environment">A Controlled Environment</h2>

<p>To truly judge the success of an experiment or trial it must be carried out in a controlled manner and <em>The Magazine</em> is far from being launched in such a manner. Marco Arment is best known for being the creator of <a href="http://instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a>, and a co-founder of <a href="http://tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>. He has a very successful podcast called <a href="http://5by5.tv/buildanalyze">Build and Analyze</a> on the <a href="http://5by5.tv/">5by5</a> network. He writes a successful blog for which he can command <a href="http://www.marco.org/sponsorship">sponsorship revenues</a>. Marco is justifiably a bit of a celebrity in the Apple world and arguably in wider technology circles.</p>

<p>Like any astute businessman, Marco has been drumming up interest in his new venture for some time now, primarily through his podcast and to his many Twitter followers. It may not be a multi-million dollar advertising campaign, but Marco has enough of a loyal following to all but guarantee the success of <em>The Magazine</em>, in the short term at least.</p>

<p>That is not the only ace <em>The Magazine</em> has up it’s sleeve: the opening lineup of writers includes well-established players such as Jason Snell, Michael Lopp and Guy English. Marco has invited submissions from other writers with openings starting from issue four suggesting that the roster of big name writers may be set up for most of his four-issue trial period.</p>

<h2 id="the-real-experiment">The Real Experiment</h2>

<p><em>The Magazine</em> is great for the readers, great for the writers and ultimately great for Marco; it should be a huge success. It’s not so great for other budding publishers waiting to see if the business model works, especially if they don’t have the following that Marco has, or the access to top writing talent.</p>

<p>It reminds me of artists like Radiohead or Nine Inch Nails experimenting with self-publishing and distribution. They declare it a success when they sell a lot of copies and state it to be the future of music publishing. It’s not so easy for the up-and-coming artist who doesn’t have the established fanbase or production talent.</p>

<p>In my opinion the real experiment here is not the success or failure of <em>The Magazine</em>. It is instead in the success or failure of Marco Arment to diversify from his roots as a developer of software into a curator, an editor and a publisher. He has expressed a dissatisfaction with writing software in the past and his forays into podcasting, writing and public speaking have indicated a desire to get away from the coal face.</p>

<p>I hope that <em>The Magazine</em> succeeds because it places an emphasis on content rather than advertising. I hope it kick starts a new business model for publishing. But as someone who likes to see an individual succeed I’m more interested in seeing how Marco’s experiment with his career pans out.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maximising Bang Per Token]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30606832645/maximising-bang-per-token"/>
    <updated>2012-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30606832645/maximising-bang-per-token</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The brouhaha over third-party Twitter clients continues with the news of the release of a <a href="http://tapbots.com/blog/news/tweetbot-for-mac-beta-sort-of">beta version</a> of Tweetbot for Mac. Just 4 days ago the <a href="http://tapbots.com/news/where-did-the-tweetbot-for-mac-alpha-go">alpha version was withdrawn</a> with Tapbots citing as a reason the “finite limit on the number of user tokens we can get for Tweetbot for Mac”.</p>

<p>This was a fair move by the developers - any Mac user could download the alpha, sign in and obtain a limited Tweetbot for Mac token. If they subsequently decided they were not interested in buying the application they can discard it without releasing the token they use. It was a problem with only one resolution - withdraw the app and preserve the tokens.</p>

<p>Today Tapbots came back with a beta version and some new rules:</p>

<ul>
  <li>new users can install the beta but they’ll not be able to add a Twitter account;</li>
  <li>users of the alpha version can use the same Twitter account they used before;</li>
  <li>users of the alpha version cannot add extra Twitter accounts;</li>
  <li>users of the alpha who revoke their access token on the Twitter site cannot add their account again.</li>
</ul>

<p>All of this makes perfect sense from the point of view of token preservation. Unfortunately in this <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/blog/changes-coming-to-twitter-api">post-announcement</a> landscape these once common items are now a scarce resource. They’ve become the fossil fuels of the technology world, and like fossil fuels they’re limited and easily wasted. They used to be very disposable - a quick look at my <a href="https://twitter.com/settings/applications">Apps section</a> on twitter.com lists 34 tokens on one account alone, and that’s after a prune earlier this week.</p>

<h2 id="efficient-token-usage">Efficient Token Usage</h2>

<p>Like many people I have a number of Twitter accounts, and on each of my clients I like to have all of my accounts signed in. This was never a problem before but now it just exacerbates the issues faced by app developers. They have a limited number of access tokens that can be used with their apps and users like me with multiple accounts end up using more tokens than other people.</p>

<p>To make an app commercially viable developers need to squeeze as much money per token as possible. One way to do this would be to increase the cost of their apps to cover the average number of accounts per user. Alternatively they could keep the initial purchase price the same while limiting the number of accounts that can be signed in through the app. Power users could then be offered the option to use in-app purchases to effectively buy extra access tokens.</p>

<p>There has been a lot of discussion recently on the devaluing of software through bargain basement prices and this is really going to hit home to Twitter client developers now. Maybe the scarcity of access tokens will encourage users to value the software higher and pay more for it. Remember, you’re not just paying for the software anymore - you’re also paying for the privilege of connecting to the service through your favourite client.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Screen Mode is Not For You]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30538198744/full-screen-mode-is-not-for-you"/>
    <updated>2012-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30538198744/full-screen-mode-is-not-for-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During a <a href="http://5by5.tv/hypercritical/82">recent episode</a> of <a href="http://5by5.tv/hypercritical">Hypercritical</a>, host John Siracusa mentioned that he had received feedback from readers of his <a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/2012/07/os-x-10-8/">OS X Mountain Lion review</a> commenting about the failings of full screen mode in Mountain Lion (and previously in Lion), particularly with respect to multiple monitor support.</p>

<p>I see where these comments have come from and have sympathy. When I first installed Lion I was eager to get stuck into this new world of full screen apps. Pressing the little button on the title bar unleashed a magical zoom animation. Some apps just stretched the existing interface, but others (such as iPhoto) changed their interface to better suit the full screen experience. It was very exciting for about 5 minutes, but it wasn’t long before I shared the frustrations aired by Siracusa and his readers:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>No, I wanna use the other screens, I wanna put stuff there, I wanna see my other windows there, I wanna see my web browser there, my Twitter feed there - whatever the heck I have over there. And you can put palettes and stuff from the application that you made go full screen, you can put them on the other screens but you can’t use them for other applications. It was like, it was almost like it was being mean to you, it’s like “I know you want to see your Twitter client, but I’m putting linen over that whole screen - nah!” and that pissed people off.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I admit that I was that reader initially and I found the lack of flexibility when using multiple displays was exceptionally frustrating. The app running in full screen mode would take over the primary display but the secondary display would only contain that boring linen background. Yes, it was possible to place extra palettes or inspectors on the secondary display but there didn’t seem to be any way to truly take advantage of the additional real estate.</p>

<p>It sure would have been nice if users could have placed two independent apps side-by-side. Or if developers could have created UI layouts that took advantage of full screen mode with multiple displays, akin to the way full screen editing was available in many previous versions of Aperture. John, being the sensible guy that he is, tried to reason it out, and I think he almost nailed it<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> when he said that full screen is for people who need to concentrate.</p>

<p>One use case I think he glossed over though is the fact that full screen is also for people who are working on portable machines. People who are working on one (possible small) screen and need to squeeze every last pixel out of their displays. It’s not for the power user who wants to work with multiple apps at once (or with a multitude of windows/palettes/inspectors from a single app). That’s what regular OS X is for and has been all along.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m going to say he nailed it, because came to the pretty much the same conclusion that I came to.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SublimeLinter - an Enabler for Lazy Programming Techniques]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30406336534/sublimelinter-an-enabler-for-lazy-programming-techniques"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/30406336534/sublimelinter-an-enabler-for-lazy-programming-techniques</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I’ve been experimenting with <em>text-editor-du-jour</em> <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2</a> in parallel with coming late to the <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Rails</a> party. Sublime Text 2 has a great plugin ecosystem that seems to be growing by the day and one plugin (or <em>package</em> in ST2 parlance) that I find indispensible is <a href="https://github.com/SublimeLinter/SublimeLinter">SublimeLinter</a>.</p>

<p>As a developer I’ve always written code in an iterative fashion - write a couple of lines, compile, edit those lines to fix the bugs, compile, write a few more lines, and so on. In my career this has occasionally been problematic, as I’ve sometimes had to work with unwieldy and inefficient <code>make</code>-based build systems that unnecessarily rebuilt large swathes of code instead of a single source file. In recent years I’ve been spoilt by some excellent IDEs (such as Eclipse/STS and Xcode) that have been kind enough to alert me to syntactical errors before I invest time in a build. </p>

<p>While playing with <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Rails</a> I found that I was regularly coming across syntactical errors only when it came to testing out the application. It wasn’t the horrible build systems of yore, but it wasn’t exactly the convenience of a nice IDE. So I hunted around for a linter that I could integrate with ST2 and quickly came across <a href="https://github.com/SublimeLinter/SublimeLinter">SublimeLinter</a>. A couple of seconds later (thanks to the ridiculously useful <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control">Package Control</a>) and I had it up and running and I was getting lots of notifications about errors in my Ruby code.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I soon realised that I was getting too many errors, to the extent that I was getting errors on perfectly valid code. The code ran fine in my Rails app, but still SublimeLinter was bitching and moaning about it. I had a look around the SublimeLinter documentation, and noticed that they recommended using the full path to the <code>ruby</code> executable if using a Ruby interpreter provided by <a href="http://rvm.io/">rvm</a>. On OS X this comes down to the fact that the default Ruby is 1.8.7 whereas most people will be using code written against Ruby 1.9.X, which they’ve usually installed themselves.</p>

<p>Thankfully SublimeLinter makes it easy to customise the Ruby interpreter to use, so if you’re having trouble with syntax errors in your Ruby code, just chose the menu item <em>Sublime Text 2 -&gt; Preferences -&gt; Package Settings -&gt; SublimeLinter -&gt; Settings - User</em>. This will open up the user preferences file for SublimeLinter and you can enter the following snippet (substituting in your own username of course, and remembering to merge the JSON with any settings you may already have in there):</p>

<pre><code>{
    "sublimelinter_executable_map": {
        "ruby": "/Users/username/.rvm/rubies/default/bin/ruby"
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>May you continue to be a lazy, iterative developer like me.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maplin 500Mb/s Powerline Adapters - A Rambling Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/29405190084/maplin-500mb-s-powerline-adapters-a-rambling-review"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/29405190084/maplin-powerline-adapters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m stuck between a rock and a hard place. I have a beautiful home of timberframe construction where every internal wall is a stud wall. What this really means is that every wall is a candidate for being stuffed full of cables. My biggest home-improvement desire is to get every room wired with Gigabit Ethernet, but if possible I’d like to get every type of cable under the sun in there. If it’s possible to generate enough heat from those cables to remove the need for central heating then I’ll consider that to be a bonus.</p>

<p>The problem is that all those lovely wall cavities are hiding behind plasterboard that my wife does not want me to remove. I’m convinced that I could do it in a surgical manner - in and out with minimal disruption and a nice new shiny coat of paint in every room. She’s convinced that I’ll leave gaping holes running down the walls that never get patched up, and that the painting won’t get beyond the colour-picking stage. She’s probably right.</p>

<h2 id="enter-stage-left-80211n-wifi">Enter stage left: 802.11n WiFi</h2>

<p>With the <em>right hardware</em> 802.11n WiFi could very easily have been the answer to my (or my wife’s) prayers. The <em>theoretical</em> maximum is 600Mb/s - it’s not quite Gigabit Ethernet, but is still capable of delivering a large amount of data quickly. Theoretically. With the right hardware.</p>

<p>At the minute I only have one weak spot in the home network - the link between a Gigabit network upstairs and a Gigabit network downstairs in the office. I invested in the latest Apple Airport Extreme base station that I paired up with a 2nd generation Time Capsule. The Airport Extreme was configured to establish a 5GHz 802.11n network using the wide-band settings.</p>

<p>I had hoped to see a pretty fast link between the two base stations, but unfortunately the data rate reported by the Extreme was just 180Mb/s. Testing the network for “real-world” performance resulted in just 93.43Mb/s (using zPerf as a test tool). This isn’t a bad speed, but I do tend to fling a large amount of data around the network. It also gets extremely frustrating to be limited to Fast Ethernet speeds when I know there’s a Gigabit network up there just waiting to be saturated.</p>

<h2 id="enter-stage-right-powerline-networking-adapters">Enter stage right: powerline networking adapters</h2>

<p>I’d considered powerline adapters in the past, but had always balked at the relatively low speeds they offered. Having discovered just how poor the WiFi connection was I decided that the newer 500Mb/s models might be worth a blast - even at 50% of the theoretical maximum I could still get 2.5 times the performance of the WiFi link. When an offer for <a href="http://www.maplin.co.uk/500mbps-twin-powerline-starter-kit-626154">Maplin powerline network adapters</a> came up they were hastily purchased. Once received I got to testing, and the results were extremely disappointing.</p>

<p>I know that the 500Mb/s is an ideal scenario and many things will conspire to reduce this figure in the real world. Old wiring, interference from other devices and use of extension cables amongst other factors. Our home is fairly modern, and has wiring that is only 8 years old. I tried to improve things by avoiding extension cables, and plugging directly into the mains sockets at both ends, but to no avail. The best rate I could get was a paltry 53.21Mb/s. WiFi it is then.</p>

<p>Not wanting to return the product without trying to find a use for it, I decided to try using the powerline adapters to connect my ADSL modem/router from downstairs to the upstairs network. We only get 5.5-6Mb/s from our ADSL connection so 50+Mb/s is plenty of bandwidth. Unfortunately since doing so, I noticed regular breaks in the connection from the home network to the ADSL router.</p>

<p>The only new factor there is the powerline adapters, so they’ve had to come out and are currently on their way back to Maplin. Rather than post them, my kind wife agreed to drop them into the store as she was going to be passing it. She’ll probably be away for a few hours at least. Now to find my hammer, some Cat6, and the crimping tool.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why App.net?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/29224063502/why-app-net"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/29224063502/why-app.net</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> is a hot topic of conversation at the minute in the intersection between the Twitter and Apple worlds that I like to inhabit<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Just over a month ago, Dalton Caldwell wrote a blog post entitled “<a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/what-twitter-could-have-been">What Twitter Could Have Been</a>”. While this initial post could be viewed as a bit of a complaint or a moan, it was also something of a catalyst. He soon followed up with a post that may go down in Internet history: “<a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/an-audacious-proposal">Announcing an Audacious Proposal</a>”.</p>

<p>In this post Dalton essentially proposed building a new Twitter. A Twitter that was funded directly by the users instead of by the advertisers. He and his company established a KickStarter-style campaign to raise $500k by 13th August in order to fund this new social network. As of the time of writing, there are just under two days remaining, and there is only $69,200 left to be raised.</p>

<p>I’ve decided to back this project because, like Dalton, I’m concerned about what I perceive as a  “degradation” of Twitter. It’s not a degradation for many people - in fact Twitter is probably going from strength to strength in the eyes of many of it’s users. But I’m an atypical user. I’m not on Twitter to follow celebrities, to track mainstream news, or to keep up with my friends. I’m mainly on Twitter to receive tech news, to use innovative apps, and to communicate with other people in the tech industry - the industry that is both my livelihood and my passion.</p>

<p>For <em>me</em>, Twitter is degrading. For <em>me</em>, it is becoming less vital, and is in danger of becoming unusable to me. I may be over-reacting, but Twitter’s recent rumblings about third-party clients has not inspired confidence. I use TweetBot for iOS (and now for Mac) fanatically. I don’t want to go back to Twitter’s first-party clients, partly because Twitter are not putting in the effort to maintain them, and partly because I don’t want to use apps that are really just conduits to the advertising model that will become essential to Twitter’s survival. Like many others, I would be happy to pay for access to Twitter, but we’re not being offered this opportunity.</p>

<h2 id="so-why-appnet">So Why App.net?</h2>

<p>I don’t know if <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> can work but I’m happy to put my money where my mouth is, and give it a chance to succeed.</p>

<p>I’m keen to join a social network at the beginning and help it grow. I joined Twitter in 2009 and while I’ve enjoyed my time on it, I sometimes feel like I missed the halcyon days when it was a closer, more tight-knit community. </p>

<p>I’m happy to pay to be part of a smaller community with a more focussed group of users. Part of the problem with Twitter is that there is no barrier to entry. Yes, this is me being a little bit elitist but I feel that it is a valid point. Every day on Twitter I am being subjected to random followers who have no interest in what I have to say. I hope that the <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> community will be more focussed and less likely to resort to such behaviour. I’m also hoping that the <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> ecosystem will be subject to more moderation - where “spam followers” can be reported and ultimately warned and/or banned.</p>

<p>I’m hoping that the requirement to pay a fee will weed out a large number of the people who try to use Twitter as a conduit to spam. Twitter is like email, in that there is very little barrier to entry to start spamming. It’s effectively free to send emails or tweets as spam if you can cover your tracks. Twitter spam is a huge problem in my eyes. I’m subjected to daily @reply spam. I’m hoping that the requirement to pay for the service will reduce the number of spammers who will target <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a>, or at the very least make it easier to track and remove these spammers.</p>

<p>I’m interested in a service that transcends Twitter and, because it is paid for by the users, will listen to those users in implementing the features that they need, or want. If done right, it will be directed by the needs of the people who <em>use</em> the service, not the people who wish to sell advertising on the service.</p>

<h2 id="huge-responsibilities">Huge Responsibilities</h2>

<p><a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> is an ambitious venture. Just getting to $500k does not guarantee any level of success. And while the developer community, or the hacker community, or the whatever-we-are community can drive the success of many things, even we can’t make it succeed through goodwill alone. The threshold may be met, but unless we embrace the resulting service, building the apps, tools, and sites to make it succeed, then it will be doomed to failure.</p>

<p>We’re also putting a lot of faith in the ability of Dalton Caldwell and his team. The fact that funding comes directly from the users means a lot, but this is still not some kind of democracy where every paying customer gets a vote. We’re not shareholders. We don’t belong to a board of directors. We are putting our hard-earned cash on the line, and trusting <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> to make the right decisions, to implement the necessary features, and to implement them on time.</p>

<p>So let’s all pull together. <a href="http://join.app.net/">App.net</a> who will build the infrastructure. The developers who will build applications to use the infrastructure. And finally the community who will use the applications. We all have a responsibility for the success or failure of this venture.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m sure it’s a hot topic in other areas too, but I can’t really say much about that.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q. When is Apple news not actually news?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28971024283/q-when-is-apple-news-not-actually-news"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28971024283/q-when-is-apple-news-not-actually-news</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A. When you report old “news” as though it just “finally” happened.</p>

<p>Mike Schramm at <a href="http://www.tuaw.com">TUAW</a> posted the following last night:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Apple has finished smoothing out its Xcode releases with version 4.4.1, which finally brings Xcode out as a standalone app.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For some bizarre reason, Mike seems to have completely missed the Xcode 4.3 release that first introduced the concept of a standalone Xcode. (He also missed the 4.3.x point releases as well). Seems like sloppy “reporting” to me.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, as Apple has grown in stature, the number of websites covering Apple news grows at the same time. Venerable Apple news sites like TUAW are competing with upstart sites, and there seems to be a scrambling to report the tiniest little details as news.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The (Mountain) Lion And The Mouse]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28825879449/the-mountain-lion-and-the-mouse"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28825879449/the-mountain-lion-and-the-mouse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mountain Lion has been running really well on <em>almost</em> all the machines I’ve installed it to, with just one exception - my (employer’s) 17” MacBook Pro. This is unfortunate, as it’s the machine that I spend the most time on - if it’s not running smoothly I feel the “pain” all day, every day.</p>

<p>Specifically I was experiencing severe cursor lag when using the mouse (or trackpad) on an intermittent basis. It wasn’t caused by any one application that I could isolate, but some apps did seem to trigger it more frequently. I couldn’t see anything under Activity Monitor to indicate what the problem could be - there were no CPU or I/O spikes. I resolved to just sit it out waiting for the inevitable 10.8.1.</p>

<p>Then I experienced a bout of constant lag. At first it seemed like a curse, but I realised that I had a recently booted system with few applications running - this is as close as I get to laboratory conditions. A quick glance at the process list showed that only one was running a little high - <a href="http:://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. It was only consuming 17% of a single core, but it still seemed a little high. When I finally got the cursor under control I was able to quit Dropbox and the lag ceased immediately. I’m guessing it might have been something to do with the methods by which Dropbox monitors the filesystem for changes.</p>

<p>A quick inspection of the Account pane under the Dropbox preferences revealed that I was still running the 1.4.7 version, rather than the Mountain Lion-compatible 1.4.12. This wasn’t all sloppiness on my part - as usual Dropbox have said that the clients should auto-update, but, also as usual, Dropbox’s auto-update facility is woefully behind the time.</p>

<p>All good <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_and_the_Mouse">fables</a> need a moral, so here goes: <em>“If your Dropbox client hasn’t updated itself, then you might want to do so manually.”</em></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>If you’ve not yet used Dropbox and would like to sign up, here’s a <a href="http://db.tt/LNlAuHd">referral link</a>.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[php-mcrypt on Mountain Lion]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28261274431/php-mcrypt-on-mountain-lion"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28261274431/php-mcrypt-on-mountain-lion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was having a few PHP problems post-Mountain Lion upgrade. Specifically I couldn’t get any sites working that utilised <code>mcrypt</code> with PHP.</p>

<p>Executing <code>php</code> at the command line told me the following:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>PHP Warning:  PHP Startup: Unable to load dynamic library ‘/usr/local/Cellar/php53-mcrypt/5.3.13/mcrypt.so’ - dlopen(/usr/local/Cellar/php53-mcrypt/5.3.13/mcrypt.so, 9): Library not loaded: /usr/lib/libltdl.7.dylib
 Referenced from: /usr/local/Cellar/php53-mcrypt/5.3.13/mcrypt.so
 Reason: image not found in Unknown on line 0</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I decided to reinstall Jose Gonzalez’ convenient php53-mcrypt formula. Post install, the PHP was able to start up without error and a quick <code>otool -L</code> on <code>mcrypt.so</code>revealed that it no longer had a dependency on <code>libltdl.7.dylib</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mountain Lion's New Archive Folder]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28287324457/mountain-lions-new-archive-folder"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.chatswood.org.uk/post/28287324457/mountain-lions-new-archive-folder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today I was unable to find one of my IMAP folders. I immediately felt a flush of panic as this folder was entitled <em>Archive</em>, and is where I keep a large number of important emails (site registration details, software license keys, etc). I have a backup, of course, but it’s still a little bit alarming to think that a folder has just disappeared.</p>

<p>The panic was short-lived as I soon noticed that under <code>MAILBOXES</code> section in Mail.app a new meta-folder had appeared called <em>Archive</em> containing sub-directories for iCloud and my IMAP server. All my important archive material was present and correct. I’d recently upgraded from Lion to Mountain Lion, and I assumed that this was a new feature.</p>

<p>As any good Mac nerd would do, I quickly tweeted about it, and then sent a message to <a href="http://twitter.com/siracusa">John Siracusa</a> as a little extra info following his monster <a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/2012/07/os-x-10-8/">Mountain Lion review</a>. I was surprised when he retweeted it, but as can expected when retweeted to 24,000 people, I soon got a few replies.</p>

<p>A number of people have suggested that this is not new, and was present in Lion as well. I can’t speak for other people, but I know that across 4 machines running every version of Lion (from 10.7.0 to 10.7.4) I did not once see this behaviour. I was able to reboot into a Lion installation and view the same setup and saw the previous behaviour.</p>

<p><img src="http://content.chatswood.org.uk/photo/2012/07/Mail.app%20-%20Lion.png" alt="Mail.app - Lion" /></p>

<p>Viewing the same setup in Mountain Lion looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="http://content.chatswood.org.uk/photo/2012/07/Mail.app%20-%20Mountain%20Lion.png" alt="Mail.app - Mountain Lion" /></p>

<p>Maybe this did appear in some form in Lion, but definitely not for my particular setup. I’m still calling it a new feature, even if it’s only new for my specific set of conditions.</p>

<p>In fact, that would be even better. That means Apple did it just for me.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
