<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: OS X | Chatswood]]></title>
  <link href="http://chatswood.github.com/blog/categories/os-x/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chatswood.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-18T11:47:28+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://chatswood.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Maurice Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The (Mountain) Lion And The Mouse]]></title>
    <link href="http://chatswood.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/the-mountain-lion-and-the-mouse/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://chatswood.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/the-mountain-lion-and-the-mouse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mountain Lion has been running really well on <em>almost</em> all the machines I’ve installed it to, with just one exception - my (employer’s) 17” MacBook Pro. This is unfortunate, as it’s the machine that I spend the most time on - if it’s not running smoothly I feel the “pain” all day, every day.</p>

<p>Specifically I was experiencing severe cursor lag when using the mouse (or trackpad) on an intermittent basis. It wasn’t caused by any one application that I could isolate, but some apps did seem to trigger it more frequently. I couldn’t see anything under Activity Monitor to indicate what the problem could be - there were no CPU or I/O spikes. I resolved to just sit it out waiting for the inevitable 10.8.1.</p>

<p>Then I experienced a bout of constant lag. At first it seemed like a curse, but I realised that I had a recently booted system with few applications running - this is as close as I get to laboratory conditions. A quick glance at the process list showed that only one was running a little high - <a href="http:://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. It was only consuming 17% of a single core, but it still seemed a little high. When I finally got the cursor under control I was able to quit Dropbox and the lag ceased immediately. I’m guessing it might have been something to do with the methods by which Dropbox monitors the filesystem for changes.</p>

<p>A quick inspection of the Account pane under the Dropbox preferences revealed that I was still running the 1.4.7 version, rather than the Mountain Lion-compatible 1.4.12. This wasn’t all sloppiness on my part - as usual Dropbox have said that the clients should auto-update, but, also as usual, Dropbox’s auto-update facility is woefully behind the time.</p>

<p>All good <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_and_the_Mouse">fables</a> need a moral, so here goes: <em>“If your Dropbox client hasn’t updated itself, then you might want to do so manually.”</em></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>If you’ve not yet used Dropbox and would like to sign up, here’s a <a href="http://db.tt/LNlAuHd">referral link</a>.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
